In Brazil, there's a whole set of elements that have been formulated
Tenemos un conjunto de elementos en Brasil
and developed by the elite to place the black wherever they wanted.
que fueron creados, elaborados por esa elite para poner al negro en el lugar que ellos quisieran.
We have a state governor who lives in a palace, right?
Tenemos a un gobernador que está en un palacio, si?
The Bandeirantes Palace, our governor official residence.
El Palacio de los Bandeirantes.
If we take the story behind it we'll understand
Si miramos a la trayectoria de eso nos vamos a dar cuenta
why the governor is in the Bandeirantes Palace
porque es que el gobernador está en el Palacio de los Bandeirantes
and the blacks are in Fundação Casa, Brazil's juvenile detention center,
y los negros están en la Fundação Casa
which is pretty antagonistic if we think of a path of humanization,
Que, en el proceso de las relaciones sociales de humanización, son antagónicos, no?
isn't it? Fundação Casa, the prisons, the female prisons...
Porque la Fundação Casa o las cárceles, las cárceles femeninas, las Fundações Casas
they're places of confinement
son lugares de encajonamiento
where people are thrown in there.
a los que ellos son tirados.
And the governor is in a palace...
Y entonces el gobernador está
It's still like an imperial-like atmosphere, isn't it?
Aun nos remete a esa cosa con un aire imperial, no?